<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Vittorio Mattei</title><link>https://vittoriomattei.com/</link><description>Vittorio Mattei's personal website and blog. Software engineer talking about programming, design, python and the IT world.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vittoriomattei.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Python configuration parameters with AWS</title><link>https://vittoriomattei.com/2022/python-aws-introduction-to-config-parameters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://vittoriomattei.com/2022/python-aws-introduction-to-config-parameters/</guid><description>Loading configuration parameters in your program is an operation that every developer will probably implement at some point while writing code.
While the code can be as simple as CONSTANT = value, this is probably not the best idea of how to implement a configuration for your software.
In this article I want to analyze some concepts that you can use for your implementation. The implementation used here will show how to apply those concepts when using Python, AWS and boto3 as your tech stack.</description></item><item><title>Python if-else alternatives for better design</title><link>https://vittoriomattei.com/2022/python-if-else-alternatives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://vittoriomattei.com/2022/python-if-else-alternatives/</guid><description>There is no doubt that one of the first conditional construct a programmer will encounter is the if-elif-else construct.
While the syntax may change across languages, the logical meaning is always the same:
if condition_1: do something else if condition_2: do something different else: do something genericWhile this construct is incredibly easy to use, there are some drawbacks to it, when the logic starts expanding.
Note that obviously there isn&amp;rsquo;t a best rule, the only way to decide which solution to use is on a case by case scenario.</description></item></channel></rss>